There are some general rules to help us determine that running time of an algorithm first rule as there
loops, the running time for a loop is the running time of the statements inside the loop, including
the tests multiplied by the number of iterations.
We have taken an example before about a constant scene that burning anything to hello message inside
the loop from one to N, and we said that it is time complexity c times and and it's all of that.
Don't worry, guys.
These general rules of asymptotic analysis are at that time complexity is just a review for what we
have taken and preparing for their exercises.
So next videos?
We will start solving exercises about complexity and determine how is how these rules will affect our
problem solving.
OK, the second rule is the nested loops analyze from the inside out.
Total running time is the product of the size of all loops.
We consider it to nested loops and we said that we need to print hello message.
So from wife, Ramsey is from one to five included.
So the outer loop will run five times and the inner loop will run five times.
Every time the outer loop would run, it will run five times the inner loop.
So five times five times C is C and square.
And we said that we took the highest power, which is an C and squared term, and we remove the C,
which is the constant and we have the O and squared notation.
The third one is that consecutive statements at the time complexities to each state.
So if you have a low message, a declaration like instantiation addition, multiplication of a constant
without interfering of their data input, so you have a constant and constant state.
OK.
The first one is that, if else, statement.
So the worst case scenario or running time is this test plus either the LS part, whichever is larger.
This is very important.
Note that it is not included in the previous videos.
If you have, if else statement, we we see the complexity of F and the complexity of ours, which is
the worst case.
We took it, if else, is the the worst case.
We took that as complexity, if that if part is more is more complex or worst case.
So with so we search for the worst case for the Owls.
And if?
Statements that logarithmic complexity and algorithm all of log and.
Takes a constant time to cut the problem size by a fraction, usually by half, as an example.
We have seen that we we are not running for a loop from one to N, but we have multiplied by two or
we have similarly running a for loop from end to I.
And such that I is decreased every time by I over two.
OK.
Another example like binary search, finding word in dictionary of and pages look at the center point
in the dictionary is the words towards left or right of the center.
And repeat the process with the left or right part of the dictionary until the war is over.
And we have seen this complexity.
These generals of asymptotic analysis with the card were playing cards and we have took any big examples
about them encoding.
So we are now preparing for the exercises that we are going to do to master the complex deal with them
by solving these.